[ Music ]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; Hi, everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
My name is Dan.
我是 Dan
I'm an engineer on the
我是辅助功能组的
Accessibility Team, and I'm
一名工程师
super excited to be talking to
我非常开心能够向大家
you about Accessibility Custom
介绍辅助功能自定义操作
Actions and how they can improve
以及如何能够
the experience for people using
通过在 App 中使用
assistive technologies with your
辅助技术来增进体验的
Let's get started.
让我们开始吧
Custom actions are really great
自定义操作有
for two things.
两大优势
The first is reducing clutter in
第一个优势是减少
your app.
你的 App 中的杂乱
This is important for everyone
这对所有
that uses your app, but it's
使用 App 的人都很重要
especially important for people
但是对于那些使用辅助技术的人
that use assistive technologies,
来说尤为重要
and I'll explain why.
我后面会解释原因
The second is all about
第二个优势是关于
improving the convenience and
提升 App 中
speed of more complex
较为复杂的交互的
interactions in your app.
便利性和速度
Let's start by talking about
我们先从
reducing clutter and to do this
减少杂乱开始
I'd like to talk about
为此我想先讲一下旁白
VoiceOver is the built-in screen
旁白是一种内置的屏幕朗读器
reader we ship across many of
是我们为了方便
our products for people who are
那些盲人或低视力的人
blind and low vision.
使用我们的产品所做的
People that use VoiceOver can
使用旁白的人能够
navigate through their apps in a
通过多种方式来
variety of ways but one way
浏览他们的 App
that's particularly popular when
但是其中最受欢迎的
navigating through a new app or
浏览一个新的 App 或
interface is by swiping left and
界面的方式是左划或
right to move between the next
右划来在上一个和
and previous item.
下一个项目之间移动
I have an app I've been working
我有一个一直在做的 App
on to help me track my favorite
帮助我追踪我最喜欢的
types of peanut butter.
花生酱品类
If you were going to use this
如果你打算在不使用
app without using VoiceOver and
旁白的情况下使用这个App
we wanted to increase the rating
而我们希望提高
of the second jar of peanut
这个列表中的第二罐花生酱的评级
butter in this list, how do we
那么我们
go about doing that?
应该怎么做呢
Well, you'd probably visually
你可能会先
scan the list until you found
扫描这个列表 直到你找到
the jar you were looking for.
你想要的那一罐
You then might focus on that
然后你可能会把注意力集中在那个
cell and look for the button
单元格然后寻找一个按钮
that affords the action you want
能够完成你想要
to perform and then tap on it.
做的操作 然后你只需点击它即可
Now that may seem pretty
现在这看起来非常直观
intuitive but that's because the
但这是因为
UI affords that intuition by
UI 能够支持这一直观感觉
logically grouping the buttons
通过有逻辑地
with the cells, which makes the
把单元格与按钮整合起来
content easy for us to process
这让我们能更容易地去处理
and digest, but what if instead
和消化内容 但是反之如果
the app was laid out a bit
App 以另一种方式布局会怎样呢
Perhaps something like this.
可能是像这样的
Notice the buttons are now
请注意现在按钮
underneath the cells, which
在单元格下面
means we have a lot more content
这意味着我们需要
to scroll through.
滑动更多的内容
Additionally, it's much more
另外 按钮与
ambiguous as to which buttons
单元格的对应关系
correspond to which cells.
也更加模糊
This could very well be the
这很可能就是
experience for someone using
有人在通过旁白
VoiceOver with your app.
使用你的 App 时的体验
Let me show you what I mean.
让我来展示一下我的意思
Let's take a look at what it's
首先我们来看一下
like to use VoiceOver to
使用旁白来
navigate through one of the
对这个 App  中的某个单元格
cells of this app.
进行浏览是什么样子的
&gt;&gt; Patty's, creamy, Noster rated
&gt;&gt; Patty's creamy Noster
1 out of 5.
得 1 分 满分 5 分
Add to favorites button.
添加至收藏按钮
Decrease rating button.
减分按钮
Increase rating button.
加分按钮
&gt;&gt; After we swipe past the cell
&gt;&gt; 当我们滑动过这个单元格后
we focused on three buttons, add
我们关注这三个按钮
to favorites, decrease rating
添加至收藏 减分
and increase rating and those
和加分按钮
three buttons exist in every
而且这三个按钮存在于
single cell in this list.
这一列表的每一个单元格中
So if we were trying to find the
因此倘若我们想要找到
10th jar, we would have listened
第 10 罐 我们就需要听到
to those buttons 30 times, which
旁白读这些按钮 30 次
can very quickly get repetitive.
这种重复很快就会令人疲倦
Additionally, we have to keep in
此外我们还要
our head what the last jar of
注意记得上一个
peanut butter we heard was,
听到的花生酱是哪一罐
otherwise we don't know what
否则我们就不知道
content is going to be affected
若我们激活其中一个控制按键
when we activate one of those
哪些内容会受到影响
So let's take a look at the app
那么让我们再重新来看这个 App
only this time designed a bit
只是这一次 App 的设计有轻微区别
I've changed the buttons so that
我更改了这些按钮
they're no longer accessible to
他们不会再出现在旁白中
I've added custom actions to the
我对这些单元格添加了自定义操作
cells so that when VoiceOver
因此当旁白
lands on a cell we can swipe up
读到一个单元时 我们可以
or down with one finger to
用一个手指向上或向下划动
choose an action and then double
来选择一个操作 然后
tap to perform it.
双击来激活这个操作
Let's take a look.
我们来看一下
&gt;&gt; Patty's, creamy, Noster rated
&gt;&gt; Patty's creamy Noster
1 out of 5.
得1分 满分5分
Anna's, chunky, sugar-free,
Anna's chunky sugar-free
rated 4 out of 5.
得 4 分 满分 5 分
Actions available toggle
可选操作包括
favorite, increase rating.
添加收藏和加分
&gt;&gt; This time when we swipe past
&gt;&gt; 这一次当我们划过
the cell we just got to the next
这一单元时 我们会直接进入到
one which made it much easier
下一个单元 这让我们可以
for us to go through this
更容易地浏览
content and find what we are
这些内容 从而找到我们
looking for.
想要的内容
Once we found it, we could then
一旦我们找到想要的内容 我们就可以
drill in and pick an interaction
进一步在那里选择一个交互操作
from there, which much more
这样的方法
closely matches the experience
更贴近
we talked about earlier of
我们之前所说的
visually scanning a list.
视觉浏览一个列表的体验
So custom actions can really
所以自定义操作可以
help us reduce clutter, we
帮助我们减少杂乱
remove the repetitive controls,
消除重复性操作
and we also reduced the
我们也可以借此减少
cognitive load on ourselves
使用 App 时候的
while we were using the app.
自身认知压力
Because we're explicitly picking
因为我们可以直观地选择
an interaction after finding the
一个交互操作 当我们找到
content we want to interact with
我们想要交互的内容后
it's no longer ambiguous what
这些操作也变得
those controls do.
不再模糊
All of this simplified the
这就大大简化了操作体验
Next let's talk about how custom
下面我们来看自定义操作
actions can improve the
能如何提升
convenience and speed of more
App 中复杂交互操作的
complex interactions in your app
便利性和速度
and to do this I'd like to talk
在此之前我想先介绍
about Switch Control.
开关控制
This is another feature we ship
这是我们为
for people with limited mobility
行动不便人士开发的另一项功能
and these people can interact
这些人群可以
with their devices using as few
通过简单的一个到两个
as one or two inputs.
操作与他们的设备交互
I've added some additional
我添加了一些额外的
functionality into the peanut
功能到这个
butter app so that when we long
花生酱 App 当我们
press on a cell an action sheet
长按一个单元时 一个操作菜单
comes up with additional options
会弹出来 提供一些额外选项
including the option to send
选项包括发送
information about one of the
关于其中的
jars of peanut butter to a
一罐花生酱的信息给朋友等
friend.
我有两个开关与
the device.
此设备配对
The orange switch will move
橘黄色的开关会将
Switch Control's focus to the
开关控制的关注点移动到
next item and the white switch
下一个项目 而白色的开关
will select that item.
则负责选取这个项目
Keep in mind switches can be
要记住 开关可以
designed for a variety of
被设计用于
different needs.
满足不同需求
So, for example, someone might
比方说 有人可能会
have switches mounted to a
将开关安装在一个
wheelchair that they can
他们能够
activate with their head.
用头部操控的轮椅上
Let's take a look at what it's
让我们来看一下
like to Switch Control to send
使用开关控制来
information about that second
发送关于第二罐
jar of peanut butter to our
花生酱的信息给我们的朋友
So we can use our orange switch
因此我们可以使用橘黄色的开关
to navigate down to the second
来浏览至第二个
cell and then use the white
单元 而后使用白色
switch to select it.
开关来选中它
This brings up the Switch
这会弹出
Control Menu which provides
开关控制菜单
additional options of ways we
提供了我们可以与该单元
can interact with the cell.
交互的其他选项
We can navigate down to the page
我们可以向下浏览至
control and select it to view
页面控制
more options.
选中它可以看到更多选项
From here, we can press select
在这里我们可以按选择键
to drill in and then navigate
进入菜单然后浏览至手势
Selecting this will give us a
选择它会让我们
list of all of the gestures we
看到一系列我们
might have wanted to perform by
想要通过触屏来
touching the display.
实现的手势
From here we can navigate down
从这里我们可以浏览至
to the second row and press
第二行然后按下
select to drill in and then
选择键来进入菜单
navigate over to tap and hold.
然后选择点按并长按
Selecting this will perform our
选择它将实现我们的
long press gesture and bring up
长按手势 并弹出
our action sheet, which we can
我们的操作菜单 我们可以
then navigate through to select
从中浏览并选取
send to a friend.
发送给朋友
We'll perform the tap and we're
我们可以实现点按 然后就可以了
Now if you think about it, we
现在回想起来 我们
did all of that and we never
完成了所有操作 而我们从未
touched the display.
触碰屏幕
That's pretty cool, right?
这非常酷 对不对
But you also probably noticed
但你可能也注意到了
that that interaction normally
这一交互一般需要
takes us two taps, one long
我们做两次点按
press and one tap on the action
一次长按和一次在操作菜单中的点按
sheet and with Switch Control
通过开关控制
that took us 18 taps, but custom
需要进行 18 次点按 但是
actions can significantly reduce
自定义操作可以显著地
that number.
减少这个数字
So let's take a look again only
我们来重新看一下
this time I've added custom
不过这次我将
actions back into the app.
自定义操作添加到了 App
We'll still use the orange
我们将使用橘黄色
switch to navigate down to the
开关来浏览到
second cell only this time when
第二个单元 不过这次当
we select it right away on the
我们在
first page of the Switch Control
开关控制菜单的第一页选择时
Menu are all of the actions of
菜单上已经有了
we've implemented.
我们添加的各种操作
We can drill in, navigate over
我们可以进入菜单浏览至
to send to a friend, press
发送给朋友
select and we're done.
按下选择键 就完成了
We didn't even need to navigate
我们甚至不需要
through the action sheet that
浏览第一次弹出的
came up the first time.
操作菜单
We're right where we need to be.
我们就直接到了我们需要的地方
That was a significantly faster
这是一种明显更快的交互操作
We were able to take those 18
我们可以使用 18 次点按的方式
taps and we get all the way down
而我们也可以使之节省至
to 6 taps, which is 67% fewer
6 次点按 这比之前的点按次数
taps than before.
节省了 67%
So custom actions can provide
因此 自定义操作可以
huge wins for convenience and
大大的提升便利性和速度
We removed the cumbersome
我们删除了繁琐的手势
gestures which significantly
大大地
sped up the interaction.
加快交互速度
Additionally, we improved the
此外 我们改进了
prominence and the convenience
那些交互选项的
of those interaction options by
突出性和便利性
placing them on the first page
通过将它们放在
of the Switch Control Menu.
开关控制菜单的第一页
We didn't need to navigate
我们不需要浏览
through several submenus and try
很多子菜单
out different gestures to figure
尝试不同的手势 来弄清楚
what might be possible.
可能的选择
Instead, everything was much
反之 一切都变得
more straightforward and direct.
更加简单和直接
Now I bet after hearing all
现在我打赌在听到
these awesome advantages of
这些自定义操作的
custom actions you just can't
绝妙优势之后
wait to use them in your apps
你已经等不及在你的 App 中使用它们了
and luckily it's pretty easy.
幸运的是 这很简单
You simply override the
你只需要重写
Accessibility Custom Actions
视图中的 accessibilityCustomActions 属性
property on your view and return
然后返回
an array of UI accessibility,
一组 UI 辅助功能
custom action objects.
自定义操作对象
Each one takes in a name, a
每个对象都有一个名字
target, and a selector.
一个目标和一个选择器
Your function simply needs to
你的函数只需要
return a Boolean as to whether
返回一个布尔值判断
or not the action was successful
操作是否成功
and take in an UI accessibility
并将一个 UI 辅助功能
custom action object as a
自定义操作作为一个参数
New this year we have a version
今年我们有一个新版本的
of the API that takes in an
API 可以接受一个
action handler instead of a
操作处理器
target and selector.
替代目标和选择器
So if using a block of code
因此如果使用代码组
better fits with the design of
更适合你的 App 的设计
your app, we encourage you to
我们建议你
give this a try.
尝试一下
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Yes.
是的
Additionally, if you're going to
此外 如果你想要
use a custom action to replace
用一个自定义操作来替换
something like an accessory
类似一个单元内部的
control inside of a cell, you'll
附件控件的内容 你可能
often want to set is
需要先将
accessibility element to false
这些控件上的 isAccessibilityElement
on those controls so they're no
因此它们就不再
longer navigable by the
能通过辅助技术
assistive technology.
进行浏览
And what we talked about our
除了我们今天
VoiceOver and Switch Control in
在演示中提到的旁白和开关控制
our demos today, custom actions
自定义操作可以
can be leveraged across many of
被用于很多
the assistive technologies we
我们所提供的辅助技术
ship including full keyboard
包括全键盘访问
access and voice control which
和语音控制
are new this year.
这些都是今年全新的
I really encourage you to turn
我非常建议你将
some of these features on and
其中一些功能打开
play around with your apps to
用你的 App 尝试
look for ways custom actions can
寻找这些自定义操作能够
improve the experience.
提升体验的方式
Thank you very much.
非常感谢大家
[ Applause ]
[掌声]